Adriano Latorre 622 212 404 adriano@latorre.info

Overview

About me

Crazy about the internet and new media, I have a deep interest in communication, design and new technologies.

I feel at home working in a team with agile methodologies. I have an analytical profile and an instinct for synthesis. I am imaginative, curious and always willing to learn.

My portfolio is available at adriano.latorre.info.

Professional skills

- Web architecture, information and interaction design.
- User experience, usability and web accesibility.
- Copywriting.
- Web design.
- Video and sound editing.

Languages

Spanish NativeCatalan Native

English Full professional proficiency

Work experience

March 2014 - Today

Spines

Web architecture
Copywriting
User experience
Interaction design
Graphic design
Web design

Spines is a startup developing an application to help educational institutions, companies and people to build deep and lasting knowledge.

I have helped to build the user experience and the design, functionality and appearance of both the application and the Spines website during the last three years. I have also been in charge of writing —in Spanish and English— most of the Spines message in a multitude of web pages, blog articles and publications in social media and in *Conexiones*, the Spines newsletter.

Using agile methodologies in a self-organized team,

the spines newstetter.

September 2009 – January 2014

Arista Barcelona

Web architecture
User experience
Copywriting
Web design

Regular collaborator in brainstorming sessions to generate campaigns and creative concepts and consultant for the social media strategy of clients such as Nissan, SEAT, Oxfam Intermón, Ajuntament de Barcelona, Caprabo, Danone Yoghourtería, Dentaid, Iris Barcelona and Autopistas.com.

September 2007 – August 2009

Freelance

Web architecture Copywriting Web design Independent consulting, web architecture, copywriting and web design for clients such as Médicos Sin Fronteras and Gnoss.

March 2000 – July 2007

httpcomunicació

Web architecture
Copywriting
Web design
Multimedia development
Video editing

Website and interactive CD developer and video and sound editor in the early years. Gradually, I grew more interested in web architecture and copywriting.

Regular participant in brainstorming sessions and responsible for projects from beginning to delivery.

Clients: Abertis, Grupo Husa, Médicos Sin Fronteras, Oxfam Intermón, Arsys, Piensa Solutions, butxaca, Querida Carmen, Buff, Cibernàrium, Barcelona Activa and many more.

October 1997 – February 2000

Freelance

Copywriting

Web design Multimedia development Video editing First freelance professional projects and stable collaborations with companies such as MDK Servimedia and Spectra.

Education

September 1997 – August 2001

Multimedia Graduate at Universitat Oberta de Catalunya.

September 1996 – August 1997

Multimedia master's degree at Universitat de Barcelona – Les Heures.

September 1994 – August 1996

German philology at Universitat de Barcelona.

Contact

Phone 622 212 404

Residence Barcelona

Portfolio adriano.latorre.info

Mail adriano@latorre.info